LITO.

JOSELITO CALDA

WEB DEVELOPER / JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

PROFILE

I am self taught web developer currently based in Singapore looking for opportunities in the tech sector. Currently working as a design engineer in a manufacturing company. Looking forward to utilize my experiences and lessons in structural engineering and in life to my career as a web/software developer.

Interest in programming started when I was exposed to Visual Basic Programming at work as a structural engineer around 5 years ago. From then I studied on my free time and now looking to transition fulltime.

www.quarto.sg is a "Room for rent app" focused on listing of room

I developed quarto.asia as a capstone project to show case my skills

quarto.asia is developed using Next-JS as my frontend framework,

· Styling was managed using tailwindcss and shacdn-ui library to create

Authentication was done through next-auth enabling login via email

Address suggestions while posting was done through one map api.

Image upload was possible using cloudinary as storage.

Domain is bought using godaddy and hosted in vercel.

as a developer and also to exposed my self to other web technologies

rentals which is perfect in Singapore where there is a huge rental

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

and mongodb via prisma for my database.

Maps and markers by using react-leaflet.

CAPSTONE PROJECTS

Developer at www.quarto.asia

accesible components

CONTACT



+65 9626-5697



jlcalda23@gmail.com



lito.codes



Singapore



www.github.com/jl-calda

TECH STACK





prisma



typescript



javascript



react



expressis









mongodb





nodejs





canva

OTHER SKILLS



engineering 🛍 staad pro







costina



mathcad

EDUCATION

udemy

2018 - present

Next-JS Course, React Course, Javascript Course, Basic Web Design Course

Adamson University 2009 - 2014

Bachelor of Science In Civil Engineering Graduated as academic merit awardee.

LANGUAGES

English

Filipino

notion-clone

market.

www.jl-next-notion-clone.vercel.app

2023-present

Notion clone built with next-js, typescript and tailwind-css. Realtime interactivity done using convex, shadon-ui for frontend and clerk for auth.

messenger-clone

www.jl-next-messenger-clone.vercel.app

A Messenger clone using next-js, typescript and tailwind-css. Realtime updates via pusher and database using mongodb with prisma as ORM.

www.jl-next-netflix-clone.vercel.app

A Netflix clone created using next-js, prisma, tailwind and mongodb.

airbnb-clone

www.jl-next-airbnb-clone.vercel.app

A airbnb clone created using next-js, prisma, tailwind and mongodb with full CRUD capabilities.

twitter-clone

www.jl-next-twitter-clone.vercel.app

A twitter clone created using next-js, prisma, tailwind and mongodb.

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Design Engineer

Ruevaleur Construction Pte. Ltd.

July 2022 - Mar 2024

Design Engineer

D.S. Brown Singapore Pte. Ltd. Nov 2019 - July 2022

Associate Engineer

Fluor Daniel Philippines July 2018-Sept 2019

Engineer III

Chiyoda Philippines Corporation Deb 2014 - July 2018